[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
We're gonna assume that no labels are provided.
我们现在假定没有预设的标签
And we're gonna aim to infer groups of related articles which are Clusters.
而我们打算推断出相关文章的分组也就是集群
Here the input is gonna be a vector.
这里的输入量是一个向量
So every observation that we're plotting here is our word count vector.
这里我们标绘出的每一个观测量都是一个字数向量
And in this case, we're just looking at a very simple example with a vocabulary that
在这里 我们只讨论一个最简单的例子
only has two words.
一个只有两个词的词汇表
So we have a vector, we have word 1 and word 2.
所以我们这里有一个向量 包含单词1和单词2（的字数）
And this axis here is word 2 and this axis is word 1.
这个坐标轴表示单词2 这个坐标轴表示单词1
Of course, remember that in reality we tend to have very large vocabularies and
当然 别忘了现实中我们通常会有一个相当大的词汇表
we have these big high dimensional vectors.
因此我们会有一些超高维的向量
So, when we're plotting our observations, they're really in this high dimensional
那么 当我们画出我们的观测量时 它们其实是在这个高维的空间中的
space but for visualization, let's just look at this 2D representation.
但为了方便呈现 这里我们只看这个二维的图示
So we have a whole bunch of documents here, all represented
那么我们这里有一大堆文件
by their word counts over these two different words in the vocabulary.
全都用词汇表中的这两个不同单词的出现的次数来表示
Okay, so that's the input to a clustering algorithm, and
好的 那么这是一个聚类算法的输入量
output is gonna be cluster labels.
而输出量则是集群标签
And so what I mean is that this observation and
所以我的意思是这一个观测量
all of these observations here, [SOUND] all of these get labeled as red.
还有这里的所有这些观测量 [背景声音] 它们都被标记为红色
So maybe they get applied, some cluster label one.
那它们可能会被指定为某某第1号集群标签
So let's just call this.
让我们就这样称呼它吧
Cluster 1.
1号集群
So for every document, it's gonna get some label.
对每个文件来说 它都会得到某个标签
So that'll be labelled one.
所以这些（圈内的点）是标记为第1类
Then all of these observations here they're gonna get some other label.
而这里这些都得标成别的标签
And let's assume that this is cluster 2.
假如说这是2号集群
So this observation gets the label 2.
那这个观测量就是第2类
And all of these observations here would get the label 3.
而所有这些观测量会得到第3类的标签
So that's gonna be the output of this algorithm.
那么这就是这个算法的输出值
And maybe what you could do is post facto,
现在你可以做的是事后回溯
you could go through and look at some articles in cluster 1 and
你可以翻阅一下1号集群中的一些文章
you could say that, this cluster is really a cluster about sports.
然后说 这个集群其实是一个关于体育的集群
And I just wanna write down explicitly that this label is provided post facto.
而我只是想明确地记下来这个标签是事后回溯得到的
Okay, well this is an example
好的 那么这是非监督学习任务的其中一个例子
of an unsupervised learning task because we're operating without any labels.
因为我们的运算不需要任何（给定的）标签
All we have are observations and
我们用到的只有观测量本身
we're trying to uncover some structure in these observations.
并试图揭示这些观测量中的一些结构
So, again, just to reiterate, the input are our word count vectors and
我再重申一次 这里的输入量是我们的字数向量
the output is, for every document in the corpus,
输出量是 对语料库中的每一个文件
we're gonna associate some cluster label with that document.
我们都为其添上某个集群标签
Okay, well, what defines a cluster?
好的 那么是什么定义了一个集群呢
Well, every cluster is defined by a cluster center, so
每个集群都有一个特定的集群中心
maybe I'll mark the cluster centers with Xs.
所以我可以把这些集群中心用X来表示
And then there's the shape to the cluster, and
那么每个集群还有一个形状
these ellipses are representing the shapes of each of these clusters.
这些椭圆形表示这里的每一个集群的形状
And so, when we think about whether this observation,
因此 当我们考虑这一个观测点的时候
this observation here should be assigned to the green cluster, or the red cluster.
这个观测点应该被标记为绿色或者红色
What we're doing is we're looking at how similar
这也就相当于我们在根据这个集群的形状
this article is, to other articles based on the shape of this cluster.
来考虑这篇文章和那篇文章有多相似
So we score every observation
因此我们给每个观测点评分
based on the cluster center as well as the shape of that cluster.
评分标准是集群中心以及集群的形状
And in this case, because this cluster is, has this kind of oblong-skewed shape,
在本例中 因为这个集群的形状是有点斜长的椭圆形
it actually gets assigned to the green cluster instead of this red cluster.
这个观测点事实上应该被分到绿色的集群而不是红色的集群
But another approach which is very common
而另一个很常用的方法是
is instead of looking at the shape of the cluster, we just look at cluster centers.
不考虑集群的形状 只看集群中心
So we just measure the distance of this observation, so
所以我们只需要测量这个观测点（到集群中心）的距离
maybe let me change colors here, so this alternative approach here.
不如让我修改一下颜色 考虑这个替代方法
As we would just look at the distance of this observation to
因为我们只需要看观测点距离
the green cluster center versus the red cluster center.
绿色集群和红色集群中心的远近
And in this case, it would be very challenging to decide whether that article
在本例中 要判断这篇文章是属于绿色还是红色集群
should go with the green cluster or the red cluster.
就比较困难了
But, there are other cases like this observation here where pretty obvious
但是 在一些其他的情况下 比如这个观测点
with this metric that it would get assigned to this red cluster.
用第二种方法就很容易判断出它应该被分到红色集群 翻译: sfwlily |审阅: XXX Coursera Global Translator Community